National Theatre Conference mss. LMC 1908
Lilly Library
National Theatre Conference mss.
1932-2012
Lilly Library
National Theatre Conference
LMC 1908
30 Boxes
The National Theatre Conference mss., 1932-2012, consist of the papers of past presidents, executive secretary, and treasurer of the National Theatre Conference, an organization of American community and university theatres organized collectively to serve non-commercial theatre.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Gift. 1962, 1963, 1964, 1969, 1970, 2001, 2007, 2008
Historical Note
The National Theatre Conference is a professional association of directors of American community and university theatres organized collectively to serve the non-commercial theatre. It was established in 1931 at a conference at Northwestern University. As of 2010, membership is restricted to 150 members.
For more information on the National Theatre Conference see Balio, Tino. The History of the National Theatre Conference. [n.p.], 1968.
Scope and Content Note
Consists of the papers of past presidents, executive secretary, and treasurer of the National Theatre Conference. They consist of the files of Barclay Spencer Leatham, 1900-1981, educator, from the central office and the correspondence of past presidents: Paul Baker, 1911-2009, theatre director; Gilmore Brown, 1886?-1960, theatre director; Paul Eliot Green, 1894-1981, playwright; Frederic Charles McConnell, 1890-1968, theatre director; Lee Roy Norvelle, 1892-1984, professor; Scott Jackson Parker, 1945-, theatre manager; and, Theodore Albert Viehman, 1889-1970, theatre director. The papers of past president Sawyer Falk, 1898-1961, educator, are in the possession of the Syracuse University Library.
The collection was further enriched by David Harrison Stevens, 1884-1968, educator, who donated a bound set of the National Theatre Conference Bulletin and a complete report of all grants made in theatre and drama by the Rockefeller Foundation; by Alexander Wyckoff, 1898-1995, actor, who sent his files of valuable information on the early history of the National Theatre Conference; by Frederic Charles McConnell's correspondence as treasurer and head of the fellowship project; and by Mrs. Hallie (Ferguson) Flanagan Davis, 1890-1969, dramatist, who sent her correspondence as chairman of the New Playwright Project.
Also included are papers pertaining to the Appraisal Project conducted by the National Theatre Conference, 1958-1965, and material dealing with dissertations, papers and replies to a questionnaire from members of the organization, 1945-1964.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Correspondence; II. Community Theatre; III. University Theatre; IV. Placement Service; V. Conferences/meetings; VI. Miscellaneous; VII. Notebooks; VIII. Papers of past officers; and IX. Additions.
Community theater.; Theater; Indiana University -- Faculty; National Theatre Conference.; Rockefeller Foundation.; Baker, Paul, 1911-2009; Brandt, Carole Ann, 1937-2014; Brown, Gilmore, 1886?-1960; Falk, Sawyer, 1898-1961; Flanagan, Hallie, 1890-1969; Green, Paul (1894-1981); Leatham, Barclay Spencer, 1900-1981; McConnell, Frederic Charles, 1890-1968; Norvelle, Lee Roy, 1892-; Parker, Scott Jackson, 1945-; Stevens, David Harrison, 1884-1968; Viehman, Theodore Albert, 1889-1970; Wyckoff, Alexander, 1898-1995
- I. Correspondence
  - Membership Files
    - Abegglen, Homer N. (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Maxwell (Box 1)
    - Arvold, Alfred Gilmeiden (Box 1)
    - Baker, Paul (Box 1)
    - Bassage, Harold Edwin (Box 1)
    - Bell, Campton (Box 1)
    - Bentley, Eric (Box 1)
    - Bentley, Warner (Box 1)
    - Boettcher, Henry Ferdinand (Box 1)
    - Bricker, Herschel (Box 1)
    - Brown, Gilmore, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Burleigh, Frederick (Box 1)
    - Carlson, Bramer (Box 1)
    - Carrington, Frank (Box 1)
    - Cattell, Mary (Box 1)
    - Cisney, Marcella (Box 1)
    - Clark, Barrett Harper, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Cloetingh, Arthur Charles (Box 1)
    - Cole, Art (Box 1)
    - Coray, Jerome (Box 1)
    - Crouse, Edward (Box 1)
    - Davis, Gordon (Box 1)
    - Davis, Hallie (Ferguson) Flanagan (Box 1)
    - Deeter, Jasper (Box 1)
    - Dolman, John, Jr. (Box 1)
    - Drummond, Alexander M. (Box 1)
    - Duerr, Edwin (Box 1)
    - Duvey, Eliot (Box 1)
    - Evans, Dina Rees (Box 1)
    - Falk, Sawyer, (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - Fort Bragg Project (Box 1)
    - Fowler, Frank (Box 1)
    - Freedley, George, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Freud, Ralph (Box 1)
    - Fuchs, Theodore (Box 1)
    - Gage, Richard N. (Box 2)
    - Gard, Robert (Box 2)
    - Gassner, John Waldhorn (Box 2)
    - Genus, Karl (Box 2)
    - Giffen, Gordon (Box 2)
    - Gilder, Rosamond, (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Glick, Carl (Box 2)
    - Gnesin, Maurice (Box 2)
    - Goates, Wallace (Box 2)
    - Green, Paul Eliot, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Haldene, Verner (Box 2)
    - Harris, Jack (Box 2)
    - Hatfield, Jack (Box 2)
    - Heffner, Hubert (Box 2)
    - Heinlein, Mary Virginia (Box 2)
    - Houghton, Norris (Box 2)
    - Hughes, Glenn Arthur (Box 2)
    - Humble, Thomas B. (Box 2)
    - Isaacs, Edith J.R. (Box 2)
    - Itkin, David (Box 2)
    - James, Burton W. (Box 2)
    - Jelliffe, Russell (Box 2)
    - Job, Thomas (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Albert Edward (Box 2)
    - Jones, Margo (Box 2)
    - Jones, Rupel J. (Box 2)
    - Kase, Charles Robert (Box 2)
    - Keeler, Jane (Box 2)
    - Kerr, Walter Francis (Box 2)
    - Koch, Frederick Henry (Box 2)
    - Koch, Fred, Jr. (Box 2)
    - Lane, J. Russell (Box 2)
    - Lang, Lester (Box 2)
    - Lauterer, Arch (Box 2)
    - Lavery, Emmett (Box 2)
    - Leathem, Barclay Spencer, (8 folders) (Box 2)
    - Lee, Warren Marion (Box 2)
    - Lees, C. Lowell (Box 2)
    - Leverton, Garret H. (Box 2)
    - Lindemulder, Gerhardt (Box 2)
    - Lippman, Monroe (Box 2)
    - McCleery, Albert Kenny (Box 3)
    - McConnell, Frederick Charles, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - MacGowan, Kenneth (Box 3)
    - McKeen, Hale (Box 3)
    - Mabie, Edward Charles, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Marroney, Peter R. (Box 3)
    - Marshall, John (Box 3)
      General
      See: Stevens, David H. folder
    - Marye, Donald (Box 3)
    - Masters, Robert William (Box 3)
    - Meade, Ralph (Box 3)
    - Meredith, Charles H. (Box 3)
    - Merrick, James Kirk (Box 3)
    - Minter, Gordon (Box 3)
    - Morris, Mary (Box 3)
    - Nelms, Henning (Box 3)
    - Nicoll, Allardyce (Box 3)
    - Norvelle, Lee Roy, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Parke, James Hambright, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Payne, B. Iden (Box 3)
    - Pearson, Talbot (Box 3)
    - Phillips, Lawrence (Box 3)
      Barclay Leathem correspondence for USO funds.
    - Porterfield, Robert (Box 3)
    - Raines, Lester Copurtney (Box 3)
    - Reveaux, Edwrd C. (Box 3)
    - Rollins, Leighton (Box 3)
    - Rowe, Alfred (Box 3)
    - Savage, George (Box 4)
    - Schneider, Alan (Box 4)
    - Schnitzer, Robert C. (Box 4)
    - Seldon, Samuel (Box 4)
    - Semenza, Edwin (Box 4)
    - Shaver, Claude (Box 4)
    - Shuster, George Nauman (Box 4)
    - Silbiger, Norbert (Box 4)
    - Sinclair, Walter (Box 4)
    - Smith, Boyd Milford (Box 4)
    - Smith, C. Duryea, III (Box 4)
    - Smith, Joseph Fielding (Box 4)
    - Smith, Samuel Stephenson (Box 4)
    - Snapp, Robert Edwin (Box 4)
    - Spayde, Sydney Howard (Box 4)
    - Stebbins, Marian Long (Box 4)
    - Stevens, David Harrison and John Marshall, (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood (Box 4)
    - Strickland, F. Cowles (Box 4)
    - Szold, Bernard (Box 4)
    - Tarrant, L. Newell (Box 4)
    - Viehman, Theodore (Box 4)
    - Warren, George E. (Box 4)
    - Welles, Ralph Emerson (Box 4)
    - Whiting, Frank M. (Box 4)
    - Whitney, Bradford (Box 4)
    - Wilson, Kendrick (Box 4)
    - Winnie, John Ross (Box 4)
    - Windt, Valentine Barthold (Box 4)
    - Wright, Edward (Box 4)
    - Wyckoff, Alexander (Box 4)
    - Young, John Wray (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1940-1943; (8 folders) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1944-1950, May; 1944-1949; (18 folders) (Box 5)
      Includes Thompson, Hine and Flory/legal counsel, 1944-1949
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1950, June-1951; (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Chronological, 1949-1950; (16 folders) (Box 7)
- II. Community Theatre
  Scope and Contents
  Contains NTC questionnaires, programs, correspondence, clippings, etc.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by state, followed by miscellaneous subjects.
  - Alabama - Louisiana, (64 folders) (Box 7)
  - Maine - Pennsylvania, (100 folders) (Box 8)
  - Pennsylvania (cont.) - Wyoming, (33 folders) (Box 9)
  - Canada, (4 folders) (Box 9)
  - Map survey (Box 9)
  - Negro Community Theatres (Box 9)
  - Panama (Box 9)
  - Summer theatres, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Survey on theatre in cities of 50,000 or more: cities with theatres (Box 9)
  - Survey on theatre in cities of 50,000 or more: cities without theatres (Box 9)
  - Questionnaire to community theatres, 1941, by state, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, including festivals, high school plays, etc. (Box 9)
- III. University Theatre
  Contains correspondence, programs, clippings, etc.
  Arranged alphabetically by state, followed by Canadian provinces and miscellaneous subjects.
  - Alabama - North Carolina, (77 folders) (Box 10)
  - North Carolina (cont.) - Wyoming, (41 folders) (Box 11)
  - Canada, (11 folders) (Box 11)
  - University Summer sessions (Box 11)
  - Teaching of theatre arts in college, by state, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Survey of drama courses, (3 folders) (Box 11)
- IV. Placement Service
  - Catalogs, 1948-1949; (6 folders) (Box 12)
  - Applications (alphabetical by name of applicant): (Box 12)
    - A-K, (6 folders) (Box 12)
    - L-Z, (25 folders) (Box 13)
  - Applications, 1946 (Box 14)
  - "New" applications and correspondence with applicants, 1948-1950; (26 folders) (Box 14)
- V. Conferences/meetings
  - Drama conference, 1931, May 2-3 (Box 14)
  - Minutes of Council Meetings, 1933-1936 (Box 14)
  - Annual meeting, 1938-1940; (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - Annual meetings, Board of Trustees and Executive Committee meetings, 1941; 1941-1951; (24 folders) (Box 15)
- VI. Miscellaneous
  - Play Project (Box 15)
    - Benney, Joseph.Yama Suki (Box 15)
    - Dortort, David.Monday Street (Box 15)
    - Dunne, George H.Trial by Fire (Box 15)
    - Levine, Roselyn.Vichy Aftermath (Box 15)
    - McCormack, James J.Allah's Project (Box 15)
    - Nail, Robert.Soldier's Joy (Box 15)
    - Saroyan, William.A Decent Birth, a Happy Funeral (Box 15)
  - Hallie Flanagan Davis fellowships, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - comptroller, 1942-1948 (Box 15)
  - Television Institute, 1949-1950 (Box 15)
  - Newsletters, letters to Council, form letters, blanks, (12 folders) (Box 16)
  - Play releases (Box 16)
  - Financial papers, (10 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1963 questionnaire (Box 16)
  - Balio, Tino.The History of the National Theatre Conference., (3 folders) (Box 16)
    Dissertation, related material and correspondence.
- VII. Notebooks
  Contents removed to folders.
  - Notebooks I-III., (23 folders) (Box 17)
    Community theatre questionnaires, 1963, organized by state, includes two folders of related materials.
  - Notebook VI., (12 pp.) (Box 17)
    Regional surveys, mostly by NTC members, organized by state, then Canada.
  - Notebook VII., (6 folders) (Box 18)
    General statements, alphabetically arranged by author of statement.
  - Notebook VIII. (Box 18)
  - Notebook VIII. (Box 18)
  - Surveys in progress, theatre technology, private theater schools (Box 18)
  - College/university theatre schools (Box 18)
  - University/professional collaboration, university/community collaboration (Box 18)
  - Educational theatre-general (Box 18)
  - Regional reports (Box 18)
  - Theatre conferences and meetings (Box 18)
  - Theatre school curricula (Box 18)
  - Notebook IX. Correspondence with theatre people and scholars, (9 folders) (Box 18)
  - Notebook X (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with theatre community, (4 folders) (Box 18)
  - Recordings, outdoor drama (Box 18)
  - Theatre festivals, summer theatre (Box 18)
  - Theatre communications group, theatre periodicals (Box 18)
  - Notebook XIa (Box 18)
  - Producers on- and off-Broadway, (4 folders) (Box 18)
  - Off-Broadway (Box 18)
  - Broadway (Box 18)
  - Broadway directors, (3 folders) (Box 18)
  - Notebook XIb (Box 18)
  - Chambers of Commerce (Box 18)
  - Professional theatre organizations and unions (Box 18)
  - Job opportunities, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - The Affluent Society (Box 18)
  - Notebook XIV (Box 18)
  - Theatre architecture and new buildings (Box 18)
  - New educational theatres built or planned (Box 18)
  - Urban and suburban planning re: theatres (Box 18)
  - Government, (5 folders) (Box 18)
  - Theatres and civil rights, censorship (Box 18)
  - Notebook XVI (Box 18)
  - The census, (3 folders) (Box 18)
  - Economics, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Foundation aid, (3 folders) (Box 18)
  - Survey of land-grant colleges, (4 folders) (Box 18)
  - Notebook XVII (Box 18)
  - Touring repertory, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Resident repertory, (5 folders) (Box 18)
  - Industrial theatre (Box 18)
  - Children's theatre (Box 18)
  - Theatre libraries (Box 18)
  - Religious drama (Box 18)
  - Unnumbered notebook., 1962-1963 (Box 18)
    Community theatre questionnaires, 1962-1963
- VIII. Papers of past officers
  Contains correspondence and other materials related to their term of office.
  Arranged alphabetically by various officers of the National Theatre Conference.
  - Baker, Paul:; 1959 program;; 1960 program; 1960-1961 meeting;; (7 folders), 1962 (Box 20)
  - Balch, Marston:, miscellaneous (1 folder), 1944-1950; 1966 (Box 20)
  - Brown, Gilmore: Correspondence, A-Z (4 folders); letters sent to all members; Membership files (26ff); election and membership data (Box 20)
  - Falk, Sawyer: correspondence (3 folders); photocopies - "originals in Syracuse University Library (4 folders), 1934-1964; 1945-1952 (Box 20)
  - Green, Paul: correspondence (8 folders); general; wartime programs; Fort Bragg project; war writing; war service; soldier theatricals reports, 1940-1945 (Box 21)
  - McConnell, Frederick: Alphabetical files - A; ANTA-May writing project; Army play project; B; Bulletin, (8 folders); C; Coburn, C.; conference booklet; D-F (3 folders); Falk, S.; fellowship (3 folders); Freedley, 1946-1948; 1944-1950 (Box 21)
  - McConnell, Frederick (cont.): Alphabetical files - G; Gorelick; H; income tax exemptions; incorporation; J-L (3 folders); Leathem; Mc; meetings, (5 folders); membership; N; New York tryout studio; new play project; placement service catalog; professional theatre policy; publication project; regional conferences; Rockefeller Foundation; R; S; Seldon; Stanford University; Stein; Stevens; T; touring company; trustees; U-W; The Wind is Ninety; X-Z; (4 folders), 1944-1949; 1945-1950; 1942-1955 (Box 22)
  - Norvelle, Lee: Acquisition of papers for history of NTC (4 folders); general, (2 folders); membership (2 folders); New Play project, 1960-1964; 1947-1953; 1946-1949 (Box 22)
  - Norvelle, Lee (cont.): Placement Service; tryout studios, New York; Ways and Means Committee (2 folders); general correspondence, (11 folders), 1944-1947; 1949-1958 (Box 23)
  - Norvelle Touring Company: bookings (6 folders); financial (3 folders); general,; publicity, (2 folders); purchase requisitions (3 folders); royalties; talent, 1947-1949; 1947-1948 (Box 23)
  - Parker, Scott Jackson: President; vice-President (Sidney Berger); Treasurer (Kevin Maifeld); Secretary (Gresdna Doty); agendas; annual meeting programs; archives - includes copy of The History of the National Theatre Conference, by Tino Balio and Lee Norvelle (National Theatre Conference); Board of Trustees handbook; code of regulations; correspondence and reference materials; luncheon; membership booklet; membership lists; minutes; newsletter; outstanding achievement award; Paul Green Award; Person of the Year; The Players; SWOT analysis; Stavis Award (2 folders), 1968 (Box 24)
  - Viehman, Theodore: general (5 folders); appraisal; constitution, by-laws, codes, 1960-1963 (Box 24)
  - Viehman, Theodore (cont.): ANTA (American National Theatre and Academy) (3 folders); AETA (American Educational Theatre Assoc.)/ACTA (American Community Theatre Assoc.); National Council of the Arts in Education; printed materials (Box 25)
  - NTC miscellaneous materials (Box 25)
  - NTC printed: (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous folder of printed items (Box 25)
    - National Theatre Conference Quarterly Bulletin: Apr. 1939, Oct. 1942, June 1943 (Box 25)
    - National Theatre Conference Bulletin: May 1945, Nov. 1945, Mar. 1946, Oct. 1946, Apr. 1947, Oct. 1947, Apr. 1948, July 1948, Nov. 1948 (2), Dec. 1949 (2), Mar. 1950, June 1950, Nov. 1950 (3 folders) (Box 25)
    - Bound volumes: General Education Board: Directory of Fellowship Awards for the Years, 1922-1950 [and] The Rockefeller Foundation: Directory of Fellowship Awards for the Years 1917-1950 (Box 25)
  - Brandt, Carole Ann: (Box 26)
    - Brandt - Vice President (Box 26)
    - Office of the President – To Do list (Box 26)
    - 1997 Barrie Stavis Award (Box 26)
    - files, 1998 (Box 26)
      Contains: Correspondence; membership; Press; To Do list.
    - files, 1999; (9 folders) (Box 26)
      Contains: National Theatre Conference; agenda; conference; correspondence; membership; nominations; Minutes; Players Club; Treasurer's Reports.
    - files, 2000; (10 folders) (Box 26)
      Contains: Agenda; Barrie Stavis Award; Code of Regulations; Conference; Correspondence; Membership; Minutes; Nominations; The Players Club; Treasurer's Report.
    - files, 2001; (10 folders) (Box 26)
      Contains: Agendas; Archives; Barrie Stavis Award; Code of Regulations; Conference; Correspondence; Membership; Minutes; Miscellaneous; Nominations; Outstanding Achievement Award; Paul Green Award; Person of the Year; Plaques; Players Club; Treasurer Reports.
    - files, 2002; (13 folders) (Box 26)
      Contains: Agendas; Barrie Stavis Award; Conference; Correspondence; Membership; Minutes; Nominations; Outstanding Achievement; Paul Green Award; Person of the Year; Plaques; Players Club; Treasurers Report.
    - files, 2003; (25 folders) (Box 26)
      Contains: Agenda; Barrie Stavis Award; Code of Regulations; Conference; Correspondence; Meeting; Membership; Membership List' Necrology; Nominations; Outstanding Achievement; Paul Green Award; Person of the Year; Players Club; Welcome letter to New Members.
    - files, 2004; (7 folders) (Box 26)
      Contains: Address changes; agenda; Correspondence; Nominations; "To be filed."
    - files, 2005; (9 folders) (Box 26)
      Contains: National Theatre Conference - 2005; Barrie Stavis Award; Board Meeting; Code; Conference; Correspondence; Minutes; New Member Letters; Nominations.
    - files, 2006; (5 folders) (Box 26)
      Contains: Award winners; Stavis Award; Delinquent Dues letters; President.
- Additions for 2008 (Box 27)
  - Address changes/notifications (Box 27)
  - Awards, 1991-2002 (Box 27)
  - Board of Trustees Handbook, December 1998 (Box 27)
  - Code of Regulations, 1989-2000 (Box 27)
  - Conference (meeting) schedules, 1987-2006; (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, 1989-2002; (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - Financial reports, 1989-1999 (Box 27)
  - Letterhead, 1991-2002 (Box 27)
  - Membership Bookletprepared by William Allman, Berea, Ohio, December 1993 (Box 27)
  - Membership criteria (Box 27)
  - Membership lists, 1988-2003; (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - Minutes: Annual meeting, 1987-2005 (Box 27)
  - Minutes: Board of trustees, 1987-2002; (4 folders) (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-2005 (Box 27)
  - Necrology (Box 27)
  - New Members – letters, 1987-2001 (Box 27)
  - NTC News, 1997-1999 (Box 27)
  - Nominating letters/Calls for nominations, (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - Nominations for Membership, 2001-2005; (4 folders) (Box 27)
  - Past Presidents. List (Box 27)
  - Players Club, 1989-1996; 2003 (Box 27)
  - Press Releases, 1995-2001 (Box 27)
  - Receipts (Box 27)
  - Secretarial duties, 1988-2001 (Box 27)
- Additions for 2012
  - NTC Conference Binders, (unbound) (Box 28)
    - NTC, 2004; (13 folders) (Box 28)
      - Meeting Agendas (Box 28)
      - Letter to Membership and Attachments (Box 28)
      - Players Club (Box 28)
      - New Members/Nominations (Box 28)
      - Treasurers Reports (Box 28)
      - Directory (Box 28)
      - Code of Regulations (Box 28)
      - Plaques (Box 28)
      - Person of the Year/Paul Green Award (Box 28)
      - Outstanding Achievement Award/Scholarship (Box 28)
      - Stavis Award (Box 28)
      - Correspondence (Box 28)
    - NTC, 2005; (12 folders) (Box 28)
      - NTC Meeting, 2005 (Box 28)
      - Letters to Membership (Box 28)
      - Players Club (Box 28)
      - Friars Club (Box 28)
      - Members/Nominations (Box 28)
      - Treasurers Reports (Box 28)
      - Person of the Year (Box 28)
      - Outstanding Achievement Award (Box 28)
      - Stavis Award (Box 28)
      - General Correspondence (Box 28)
      - Minutes from Meeting, 2004 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
    - NTC, 2006; (10 folders) (Box 28)
      - NTC Conference, 2006 (Box 28)
      - Letters to Membership, 2006 (Box 28)
      - Players Club (Box 28)
      - Friars Club (Box 28)
      - Treasurer (Box 28)
      - Person of the Year/Paul Green Award, 2006 (Box 28)
      - Outstanding Achievement Award/Scholarship, 2006 (Box 28)
      - NTC Stavis Award, 2006 (Box 28)
      - NTC Minutes from Meeting, 2005 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
    - NTC, 2007; (11 folders) (Box 28)
      - Conference Schedule (Box 28)
      - Meeting Minutes (Box 28)
      - Treasurer Budget and Expenses (Box 28)
      - Treasurer Membership Dues (Box 28)
      - Elegant Affairs Contract (Box 28)
      - Pre-conference Member Correspondence (Box 28)
      - Thursday - Board of Trustees Meeting (Box 28)
      - Friday – Meeting - The Players (Box 28)
      - Saturday – Luncheon -The Players (Box 28)
      - Sunday - Business Meeting - Actors Equity Association (Box 28)
      - Stavis Playwright Award, 2007 (Box 28)
    - NTC (continued), 2007; (8 folders) (Box 28)
      - Guest Speakers, 2007 (Box 28)
      - NTC Code of Regulations (Box 28)
      - Membership Directory (Box 28)
      - Registration and Attendance Responses (Box 28)
      - New Member Nominations and Correspondence (Box 28)
      - Date Change Correspondence and Ballots (Box 28)
      - Conference Schedule and Minutes, 2006 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - NTC Bulletins
    - June 1939 - June 1940 (Box 28)
    - Oct. 1940 - Dec. 1940 (Box 28)
    - April 1941 - June 1941 (Box 29)
    - Oct. 1941 - Oct. 1942 (Box 29)
    - Dec. 1942 - April 1943 (Box 29)
    - June 1943 - April 1944 (Box 29)
    - June 1944 - Oct. 1944 (Box 29)
    - Jan. 1945 - Nov. 1945 (Box 29)
    - March 1946 - June 1947 (Box 29)
    - Oct. 1947 - Nov. 1948 (Box 29)
    - March 1949 - Aug. 1949 (Box 29)
    - Oct. 1949 - Dec. 1949 (Box 29)
    - March 1950 - June 1950 (Box 29)
    - History of NTC, Miscellaneous, Nov. 1950 (Box 29)
- 2018 Additions
  - Annual Meeting - minutes, nominations, and programs, 2002 (Box 30)
  - Annual Meeting - minutes, nominations, and programs, 2003 (Box 30)
  - Annual Meeting - minutes, nominations, and programs, 2004 (Box 30)
  - Annual Meeting - minutes, nominations, and programs, 2005 (Box 30)
  - Annual Meeting - minutes, nominations, and programs, 2006; (2 folders) (Box 30)
  - Annual Meeting - minutes, nominations, and programs, 2007; (2 folders) (Box 30)
  - Annual Meeting - minutes, nominations, and programs, 2008 (Box 30)